Lynchburg Va, 24502 (540) 524-0245

charlestbell@gmail.com

GitHub - https://github.com/charlestbell

Linkedin - https://www.linkedin.com/in/c-t-bell-9b03bb63/

# C.T. Bell

## **SUMMARY:**

Full Stack web developer with a certificate from the UCR Bootcamp. 1 year of JS experience, 5 years of ecommerce experience and 10 years of video marketing experience. Fluent in JS, Node, Mongo, Express, React, React Native, HTML5, CSS and SQL. A life-long learner with a passion for user experience and design. Excellent communicator. Highly creative and able to understand complex systems. Experience with Agile Development, TDD and kanban. Known for being adaptable and learning new things quickly.

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

CODING: Node, Mongo, Express, React, React Native, SQL, HTML5 and CSS

TOOLS: GIT, Heroku, Firebase, Photoshop

# PROJECTS:

Character Tavern A guided dnd character creator with custom pixel graphics |
React, Mongo, Express, Heroku

Live Site - https://character-creator-tavern.herokuapp.com/ Repo - https://github.com/Hammonds526/CharacterCreator

 Dablr A social education platform that aggregates the best tutorials on every topic. | Sequelize, SQL, JQuery, Bootstrap

> Live Site - https://dabblr-tutorials.herokuapp.com/ Repo - https://github.com/Relten98/Dabblr

 ctyFaktz A data-driven dashboard that generates interesting facts about any city on the fly | Materialize, jQuery

Live Site - https://charlestbell.github.io/ctyFaktz/

Repo - https://github.com/charlestbell/ctyFaktz

Weather Dashboard A beautiful and personal weather dashboard | Bootstrap, jQuery

Live Site - https://charlestbell.github.io/Weather-Dashboard/

#### **EXPERIENCE:**

# Web Admin/Marketer/Content Creator - Employee Blue Ridge Overland Gear

2016-2021 Lynchburg, VA

March 2016 - Present

- Planned, produced and edited over 300 Youtube across multiple brands, channel went from 1k subscribers to well over 20k
- Helped to craft the brand identity, developing messaging, strategies and marketing materials and helped take the company from 6 employees to 16 and triple it's sales.
- Helped facilitate a successful website replatforming. Worked on database transfer, content audit and implementation for various brand needs. Quickly became the go-to person for technical needs.

## Freelance Film Crew

2010 - 2016 Virginia area

 Worked on content and marketing for countless brands and several award winning film projects.

# **EDUCATION**

Full Stack Web Development Certificate UCR	Nov 2020 - April 2021
Udemy Course - Master Git and GitHub - Beginner to Expert	May 2021
Testing React with Jest and Testing Library	Sep 2021
React Native - The Practical Guide [2021 Edition]	Sep 2021

#### **AWARDS**

CyberPatriot Team Lead - 2nd in Virginia 2011